8 Years Ago 2009 a.t.b.
神聖ブリタニア帝国 第十七皇位継承者
ルルーシュ・ヴィ・ブリタニア様
Announcing Prince Lelouch vi Britannia,
17th heir to the Royal Britannian Imperial throne!
御入来
マリアンヌ后妃は ブリタニア宮で
殺められたと聞いたが
I heard Empress Marianne was killed
inside of the Britannian palace.
There's no way terrorists
could have just gotten in there!
テロリストが簡単に
入れるところではありませんが
Then, the real killers
must have been...
では 真の犯人は
怖い怖い そのような話
探る事すら恐ろしい
Beware, my friend! You'll regret
starting rumors like that around here!
しかし 母親が殺されたというのに
しっかりしておられる
And yet he seems so steadfast,
even though his mother is dead!
But he has no path to the throne now.
だが もうルルーシュ様の目はない
And the Ashford family who
backed them is finished, too.
後ろ盾のアッシュフォード家も
終わったな
And his sister, the princess?
妹姫様は？
I heard she was shot in the legs.
足を撃たれたと
And that she'd lost her sight.
お目も不自由に
心の病と聞きましたが
Hysterical blindness, though, right?
It's the same thing. She can't even
be married off for political gain now.
同じ事よ 政略にも使えぬ体
皇帝陛下 母が身まかりました
Your Majesty!
My mother has passed away!
だから どうした？
What of it?
だから？
What of it?!
You sought an audience with the emperor
of Britannia simply to tell me that?!
そんな事を言う為にお前は
ブリタニア皇帝に謁見を求めたのか？
次の者を 子供をあやしてる暇はない
Send in the next person!
I have no time to babysit a child!
父上！
Father!
イエス ユア・マジェスティ
Yes, Your Majesty!
Why didn't you protect Mother?!
なぜ母さんを守らなかったんですか？
皇帝ですよね？
この国で一番偉いんですよね？
You're the emperor!
The greatest man in this nation!
だったら守れたはずです
You should have protected her!
And now you don't even visit Nunnally!
ナナリーの所にも顔を出すぐらいは…
弱者に用はない
I have no use for weaklings!
Weaklings?!
弱者？
That is what it
means to be royalty!
それが皇族というものだ
うっ…
なら僕は 皇位継承権なんていりません
Then I don't want to be your heir!
おぉ…
I've had enough of the fighting and the
scheming over who will succeed you!
あなたの跡を継ぐのも 争いに
巻き込まれるのも もうたくさんです
死んでおる
You are dead.
うっ
お前は生まれた時から死んでおるのだ
You've been dead from
the moment you were born.
身にまとった その服は誰が与えた？
Who gave you
the clothes you wear?
Your home,
your food, your very life!
家も食事も 命すらも
全てわしが与えたもの
All of those,
I have given to you!
つまり お前は生きた事は
一度もないのだ
In short, you have never actually lived!
And yet you dare to speak
such foolishness to me!
しかるに なんたる愚かしさ！
ひーっ　うぅわー
Lelouch!
ルルーシュ
死んでおるお前に権利などない
ナナリーと共に日本へ渡れ
As you are dead,
you have no rights.
I am sending you
and Nunnally to Japan.
As prince and princess,
you will serve as bargaining chips.
皇子と皇女ならば良い取引材料だ
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間は 何時も直ぐ傍に…
Itsumo sugu soba ni
It's always right there at my side
Kakusenu iradachi to
Even as I stood still, looking at myself
隠せぬ苛立ちと
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Tachitsukusu jibun wo mitsume
With undisguised frustration
Mayoi nagara nayami nagara
Feeling lost, feeling anguished
迷いながら 悩みながら
Kuyami nagara kimereba ii sa
Feeling mournful, deciding what to do
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
Kimi ga kureta kotoba hitotsu
All it took was a single word from you
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
戸惑いは消え去り
Tomadoi wa kiesari
And my uncertainty vanished
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Karappo datta boku no heya ni hikari ga sashita
You let the light shine into what was my empty room
Miageta oozora ga
The sky I had been looking up at...
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
Aoku sumikitte yuku
Cleared and turned blue
Tozashita madowo hiraku
And I decided to throw open...
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
Koto kimeta
The windows that were kept closed
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間を 感じる今ここに…
Kanjiru ima koko ni
I feel it right here with me
ATTACK CORNELIA
第七世代のナイトメアフレームでして
その能力は通常の…
It's a seventh-generation Knightmare Frame,
making its abilities far greater than normal...
そのランスロット
パイロットはイレヴンだと聞いた
I've heard the Lancelot's pilot is an Eleven.
はい 名誉ブリタニア人です しかし…
Yes, an honorary Britannian. However...
一等兵から准尉に特進させた
それだけで満足せよ
I've granted him a special promotion
from private to warrant officer.
He should be satisfied with that.
ナンバーズなどに頼らずとも
私は勝ってみせる
I can win without
depending on any Numbers.
命を懸けて戦うからこそ
統治する資格がある
Those who risk their lives
in combat deserve to rule.
その理屈は分かります お姉様
I understand the theory,
Sister, but still...
でも…
すみません 宿題まで見てもらって
I'm sorry you have to sit here
helping me with my homework.
いいのよ 普通の学校には
通っていなかったんだもの 仕方ないわ
It's all right. You haven't gone through a
normal school before, so it can't be helped.
生徒会の人にも
教えてもらっているんですが なかなか…
The guys on the student council are
helping me too, but it's still kind of hard.
うっふふふ
ホント言うとね ちょっと心配してたの
To be honest, I've been a little worried.
フランクな学校とはいっても
馴染めないんじゃないかって
I've heard it's a fairly liberal school,
but I was wondering if you weren't fitting in well.
僕も覚悟してました
I was prepared for that.
でも偶然 昔の友達がいて
彼がきっかけを…
But, just by chance, I ran into an old friend
there, and he smoothed things out for me.
その友達 大事にしなさい
Value that friend.
２人の友情が続けば
再会は偶然じゃなくて必然になるの
If your friendship continues, your reunion will
turn from a coincidence into an inevitability.
はい
Right.
ねっ それ食べてみて
Anyway, try one!
あぁ ありがとうございます
Thank you!
感想を聞きたいんだけど
I'd like your opinion on them.
ジャム？
Jam?
いいブルーベリーが手に入ったの
I got some lovely blueberries!
はーい
Okay!
解散 解散！　今日は出番なし！
Pack it up! Pack it up!
We're doing nothing today!
おーめーでーとー！
Hip-hip-hooray! That's all, folks!
おしまい！　はぁー
えーっと…
Um...
うっふふ
学校 行ってきなさい
Go to school.
今日の授業は終わってるけど
友達に会うって事も大事なんだから
Classes might be over for today,
but it's important to meet your friends, too.
ねえ 大事な事聞いてもいいかな？
Say, can I ask you
something important?
ん 何？
Hm? What?
カレン 私達に隠し事してない？
Kallen, are you hiding
something from us?
えっ？
いいよ 隠さなくても
You don't have to.
いやぁ なんの話？
No. What are you talking about?
話してよ　私 驚かないから
Just tell me. I won't be shocked.
この間ね 見ちゃったんだ
You see... I saw you before.
う…
付き合ってるんでしょ ルルと！
You're dating Lulu, right?!
ルル？
Lulu?!
だって こないだ校庭で…
Well, that time on campus!
違う違う 待ってよ
あれは向こうが勝手に…
No! No! Hold on!
That was all his doing!
ルルから？
Lulu did it?!
いやー そんなんじゃなくて…
No, it wasn't like that.
でも この前だって
その猫捕まえようとして
But, you were trying so hard
to catch the cat before, so...
あれは違うでしょ
No, that wasn't it.
Besides, a kiss isn't such a big thing...
それにキスぐらいでそんな…
ぐらいって… じゃあそれ以上の？
It's not?! You mean you've
done more than that?!
へっ 違う　変な想像ストップ！
周り見えてなさ過ぎ！
No! Quit imagining things!
You're reading way too much into this!
だからお見合いの事は…
But, an arranged marriage is just!
分かってる アッシュフォード家を
立て直したいって話は
I understand how you want to
reestablish the Ashford family...
でもね お母さん
But, Mother!
あっ 分裂した！
Ah! I've split it!
サイタマゲットーの包囲 完了しました
The Saitama ghetto is
now completely surrounded.
ヤマト同盟のアジトは
この内側にあります
The Yamato Alliance's
hideout is in here.
近隣住民の半数以上は彼らの協力者
これでしたら…
Half the people in this neighborhood
are cooperating with them.
In this situation...
総生産への影響は？
What will be the effect
on overall production?
第１次が 0.2のマイナスになります
Primary sector output should
decrease by 0.2%
予想範囲内か… よし
Within expectations,
you mean? Very well...
貴兄らは あのシンジュク事変に
参加していたのだったな？
You all participated in
the Shinjuku incident, correct?
はっ コーネリア殿下の慈悲を
賜りまして
Yes, and we appreciate
your great mercy, Princess Cornelia...
そんな話ではない
That's not what I'm asking!
Don't you think this is similar?
似ているとは思わないか？
は？
シンジュクの状況に
To the conditions in Shinjuku...
軍部はテロリストの潜伏する
サイタマゲットーに対して
Military authorities report that...
they are surrounding the Saitama
ghetto, which is hiding terrorists.
包囲作戦を展開中です
コーネリア総督も現地入りした為
立ち入り制限が発令されました
As Viceroy Cornelia is on the scene as well,
entry to that area has been restricted.
うっふふ
ん？　どうした そんなに怖い顔をして
What has you looking so serious?
２時間後に総攻撃が開始される模様です
It looks like a full-scale assault
will be launched in two hours.
これにより 次の地域は…
Consequently, the following areas will
have their power cut for the time being:
なんで時間まで報道させるんですかね？
挑発しているんだよ ゼロを
They're provoking Zero.
ゼロは激情型の犯罪者だ
Zero is a criminal with a flair for the theatrical.
おびき出す為に私はあえて
シンジュクと同じ状況を作り出した
I've recreated the conditions of
Shinjuku in order to draw him out.
奴が己を過信するタイプなら
私を殺しに来るはずだ
If he's the type who's overconfident,
I think he'll come here to try and kill me.
総督！　それでは総督の命が
Viceroy! You'd risk your
own life like this?!
戦とはな 誇りと命の奪い合いだ
War is a struggle
between pride and life!
乗るつもりか 敵の挑発に
You're falling for
the enemy's provocation?
わざわざ招待してくれたんだ
Well, they took so much
trouble to invite me.
それに コーネリアには
聞きたい事もあるしな
Besides, there's something
I'd like to ask Cornelia.
ブリタニアの破壊と
母殺しの犯人を見つける事
Destroying Britannia or discovering
your mother's murderer...
お前はどっちが大事なんだ？
Which is more important to you?
同じだよ その２つは
The two are exactly the same.
ブリタニアの皇族は 次の皇帝の座を
巡って常に争っている
The Britannian royal family is competing
to determine who will be the next emperor.
いや 争わされているんだ あの男に
Or rather, they're being made
to fight. By that man!
しかし それがブリタニアの
強さでもある
Still, that is the strength of Britannia.
そうして勝ち残った最も優秀な人間が
次の皇帝になるのだから
The best person is the last one left standing,
and so they become the next emperor.
そうだ 弱者は全て失い這いつくばる
ブリタニアってのはそういう国だ
Exactly. The weak all lose
and are cast away.
That's Britannia.
That's the world they live in!
そういう世界だ
弱肉強食は 原初のルールだ
Survival of the fittest is
the most essential rule of all.
だとしたら ナナリーはどうなる
If that's true,
then what happens to Nunnally?!
弱いから諦めなくてはならないのか？
Does she have to give up
because she's weak?!
俺だけは絶対に認めない
I refuse to accept that!
そんな世界は俺が消し去ってやる…
あっ
I'll wipe out that sort of world myself!
ふっふふっふふーふ
ふーふっふふっふっふふ…
とにかく 私とルルーシュは
関係ないから
Anyway, there's nothing
between Lelouch and me!
あっ
ルルーシュ？
Lelouch?
じゃあ そういう事で
Anyway, that's how it is!
It's nothing...
なんでもないから
あ…
えっと ルルーシュは？
Um... Where's Lelouch?
知る訳ないでしょ あんな奴！
I don't give a damn where that guy is!
へっ？
行くな ルルーシュ
Don't go, Lelouch. I can't have you dying
before you fulfill your part of our bargain.
私との契約を果たす前に
死んでもらっては困るからな
言ってる事とやってる事が
違うんじゃないか？
There's a contradiction in what you
say and what you're doing, isn't there?
殺しはしない 足だけ撃って
おとなしくしてもらうさ
I won't kill you. I'll just shoot you
in the leg to quiet you down.
なるほど お前ギアスは使えないんだな
I see. You can't use the
Geass yourself, can you?
うっ
ま 予想はついていたけどな
Well, that's what I thought.
自分でやれるなら
俺に頼んだりはしないだろ
If you could do it yourself,
you wouldn't have asked me to do it.
私が銃を恐れると思うのか？
You think you can
threaten me with a gun?
恐れるさ
Yes, I can.
はっ…
俺はお前に会うまでずっと死んでいた
Until I met you, I was dead.
無力な屍のくせに
生きてるって嘘をついて
A powerless corpse
living a lie of life.
何もしない人生なんて
ただ生きてるだけの命なんて
A life where I did nothing except
the act of living day to day.
ゆるやかな死と同じだ
It was like dying a slow death.
また昔みたいに なるくらいなら…
If I'm to go back to that,
then I'd rather...
待て！
Wait!
ふっ
確かに意味はないな そんな命
I see your point.
It's meaningless. A life like that...
ぬわーっ
くそーっ！
Mayor!
なぜですか？　ここには子供だっている
Why are you doing this?!
We even have children here!
私達は何もしていないのに！
We haven't done anything!
だからだ！
Exactly why!
このゲットーの住民はテロリストの
存在を通報せず かばい隠した
Because the people of this ghetto
don't report about the terrorists!
You cover for them! Hide them!
これは統治国に対する反逆罪だ
That is treason against a suzerain state!
いーっ
責任者達の掃除が終わったようです
It seems we've finished up sweeping
away the people in charge.
うん 時間でもあるしな 始めるか
Hm... It's about time.
Shall we begin?
はっ！
Right!
全軍に告げる
Attention, all forces!
Commence eradication of the Saitama ghetto!
これより
サイタマゲットー壊滅作戦を開始する
全軍！　第１戦闘態勢に移行
All forces, assume level
one combat stations!
なぜコーネリア殿下は 我々にも出撃を
命じて下さらないのだ？
Why won't Princess Cornelia
order us to attack as well?!
オレンジがいるからだ
Because Orange is here.
えっ？
処分されないだけでもありがたいと思え
Just be glad
you weren't disposed of!
貴様のせいで 我々の道は
閉ざされたのだからな
It's because of you
that our careers are over!
しかし それはゼロが…
But, it was Zero who did it!
またそれか　ふっ
That again. Hmpf...
ゼロ… やはり学生が協力者？
Zero... Could that student
be working with him?
市街第４区は制圧を完了
Suppression of area 4, complete.
うわぁー
8th and 11th mechanized infantry companies are
sweeping north and south in a pincer movement.
きゃー
同じだ
クロヴィスがコーネリアになっても
All the same. Even when Clovis is replaced
by Cornelia, Britannia never changes!
ブリタニアは変わらない
どこの所属だ？　部隊名とＩＤを示せ
What unit are you from?
Give me your unit name and I. D!
第３偵察中隊のダリオ・トーレスです
Dario Torres, 3rd reconnaissance company.
テロリストより このようなものを
押収しました
I've recovered this from a terrorist!
本部にご送信願えないでしょうか？
Could I ask you to please
transmit it to headquarters?
ディスクか ただその前にＩＤを
確認させてもらう
A disk, huh?
Well, I need to verify your I.D. first.
分かりました
しかし こちらもその前に
Understood. However, before we do that,
I'd like to borrow your Sutherland.
あなたのサザーランドを
頂きたいのですが…
うっ
分かった 大事に使えよ
Sure thing. Take care of it.
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much.
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
外環はダメだ
The loop line's no good.
Can't we break through
along the Sai-kyo line?
埼京線は突破できないか…
装甲列車がふさいでいて…
They've got armored
trains blocking it.
農道も使えない
We can't use the farm roads, either.
アカバネかジュウジョウから援軍は？
Any reinforcements from Akabane or Jujoh?
１人ならまだしも 集団じゃ無理だ
Maybe a single man could get through,
but not a whole group!
イズミさん！
Izumi!
どうだった トダやカワグチ方面は？
Well? Any word from the
Toda or Kawaguchi districts?
それより これっ
Never mind! Take this!
ん？
Huh?!
私は ゼロ
This is Zero.
えっ ゼロ？
Zero?
ゼロって あの…
Zero? You mean?
シンジュク事変の事は聞いているはずだ
私に従え そうすれば助けてやる
I assume you heard
about the Shinjuku incident.
Do what I say
and you will be saved.
おぉ…
Ｂ12 制圧完了
B-12, suppression, complete.
Ｆ７に敵影ありません
F-7, no sign of the enemy.
Ｄ24 達成率87％
ポアドン隊は516へ転進してください
Powadon team, change course to 5-1-6.
イエス マイ・ロード 516へ転進
Yes, my lord. Moving to 5-1-6.
手応えのない
来てないのか ゼロとやらは
This is almost too easy.
Isn't Zero coming?
所詮はただのテロリストですから
Guess he's just another
terrorist in the end.
They came! They really came!
来たっ！　ホントに来た！
ゼロの言った通りだ
Just like Zero said!
さぁて コーネリアを引っ張り出すか
隙を作らせるか
Now then, should I draw Cornelia
out or make an opening?
Ｒ１ Ｒ２はそのまま後退
敵をＮ２のいる位置まで引きずり出せ
R1, R2 will continue to fall back.
Draw them back to
the area where N2 is.
Ｂ７は２時の方向に射撃
B7, open fire towards 2 o'clock.
Ｐ５のチームは斉射開始
P5's team will commence its barrage.
ゲシュター隊 通信途絶
Gester team, contact lost!
Enemy spotted in district G47!
Ｇ４-７方面に敵影を確認
カシスキー隊 交戦中
伏兵がいた模様
Kaczinski team engaging!
They were ambushed!
敵は我が軍のサザーランドをろ獲して
使用しているようです
The enemy seem to be using Sutherlands
captured from our own forces!
シンジュクの時と同じだ
It's just like in Shinjuku.
現れたのか ゼロが
Has Zero appeared?
Ｎ２ そのまま右 上方に
N2, continue towards the upper-right!
Ｒ４ 撃て
R4, fire.
Ｎ１は左のやつから
N1, take the guy on the left.
よし Ｐ３ 橋を落としてルートを断て
Right... P3, take down the bridge and close the route!
ポイント17が落とされました
Point 1-7 has fallen. Halley team, contact lost!
ハリー隊 通信途絶
ここまでだな
That's enough. Order all troops to fall back.
全部隊に後退を指示せよ
これ以上の被害は意味がない
Any further damage will be meaningless.
退却ですか？
Fall back?!
I beg your pardon,
but we can still fight them!
恐れながら まだ戦えます
戦えんよ これでは
We can't fight them like this.
全部隊に告げる
ゲットー外縁まで至急後退せよ
To all forces! Fall back behind ghetto perimeter at once!
配置は問わない
ゲットー外縁まで至急動け
Never mind holding formation!
Fall back behind ghetto perimeter at once!
なんだ張り合いのない
What, no stomach for it?
後退する部隊に紛れ込めば
コーネリア お前のすぐ近くだ
If I blend in with the retreating units,
that'll put me right next to Cornelia.
Have I cleared the conditions already?
条件は早くもクリアかな？
ふっふふ
血は争えないなぁ
It's in his blood, I guess.
しかし あのタイプは危険だぞ
果たして どちらの道に…
Still, that type of person is dangerous.
I wonder which path he'll take.
分かっている
All right, fine!
Who do you think I am, anyway?
私を誰だと思っているんだ
ふーん ルルってこのエリアができる
前からこっちにいたんだ
So, Lulu lived here before this was
an Area, huh? Was he a neighbor?
近所だったの？
And you? Um...
君は？　あっああ…
私？　似たようなもんかな
Me? Maybe I was like him, too.
ルルってなんか不真面目で 努力とか
そういうの鼻で笑ってる気がして
He seemed so frivolous and
would sneer at working hard.
正直最初は好きになれなかった
I didn't really like him much at first.
あ…
でもね 高１の時 交通事故を見かけたの
The thing is, there was a traffic accident
I saw back when we were freshmen.
どう見ても悪いのは後ろから
ぶつかった方で
Any way you looked at it, it was the
fault of the driver who hit from the rear.
でも 誰も助けようとしなかったの
But nobody tried to help out.
その時…
And then...
ルルはね それを誇る訳でも
笑い飛ばす訳でもなくって
Lulu didn't do it to boast
or to laugh about it.
いつもみたいに
つまらなそうな顔してて
He did it with the same
bored look he always has.
でね 思ったの
And that's when I wondered What is this
guy thinking? What's he want to do?
あいつ何考えてるんだろ？
何をしたいんだろ？　って
私 知りたくなっちゃって そしたら…
I wanted to know,
and then, well...
好きになっていた
You fell in love.
えっ あぁ そうなるのかな
これって…
Um... Is that what this is?
いいよねぇ 恋って
Oh, to be in love.
はぁ～あ
コーネリア 負けるのはお前だ
Cornelia... It's you who's lost.
勝つのは私だ
It's I who wins.
はあ？
はい
Yes. That's why they call her the Goddess of Victory.
総督は勝利の女神にございますれば
行くか？　我が騎士ギルフォードよ
Ready to go, Guilford my knight?
ご下命ありがたく存じます
It is my pleasure to obey, my lady.
ふっ いくらギアスがあるとはいえ
Hm...
Even with my Geass, the normal security
makes just walking in too dangerous.
通常の警備状況で進入するのは
危険すぎる
やはりクロヴィスの時と同じく
隙を作らせて…
I guess I'll have to create an
opening, as I did with Clovis.
ん？　生徒会室？　猫祭りの
打ち合わせは明日のはずだが
The student council room? I thought
the cat festival meeting was tomorrow.
カレンは違うって言うけど
I know Kallen said I had it all wrong,
なんか ごまかす為に
怒っていたようにも見えたし
but it seemed like she was
getting upset in order to fool me.
だから こういう事は本人に
直接聞くのが一番
Which is why in this case it's
best to just ask him directly.
君の事どう思ってるかも聞いてあげるよ
I'll ask him how he feels about you for you.
えっ そんなとこまで？
What?! You'd go that far?!
大丈夫 うまくやるから
Relax, I can handle him.
あー そんなのダメッ
No! No way!
ん？　まあいいか
Hm? Whatever.
いいから任せて 僕がやれば…
C'mon, let me handle this. I can do it.
嫌なの ヤダッ！
No! No way!
うまくやるから うまく… うわぁ！
It'll be fine, I swear... WHOA!
ニャーン
ご… ごめん
I... I'm sorry!
あ…
うぅ
ニャォーン
あの… 痛かった？
Um... Does that hurt?
かなり
A lot.
必死だな コーネリア
You're desperate, Cornelia.
親衛隊でなんとかしようと
Using your royal guard like this...
こちらゼロ Ｎ１のみ識別信号を回復
This is Zero. N1 only will re-engage their I.F.F. signal.
Operate as a Britannian unit.
ブリタニア機として行動せよ
分かった
Understood.
おとりとしてな
As my decoy.
信号を発するナイトメアが１機
市街地に取り残されています
One Knightmare unit transmitting an
I.F.F. signal left within the city area.
交信できないのか？
Can't you contact it?!
救護班を…
Scramble a rescue team!
破壊しろ
Destroy it.
そんな！
敵の人質になっているのかも…
You can't!
He may have been
taken captive by the enemy!
私は下がれと命じた
I ordered them to fall back.
私の命令を実行できない兵士は必要ない
I don't need soldiers
who can't follow my orders.
そういう事だ
As she says.
しかし！
But!
命を捨てても任務を遂行する
Do your duty,
even at the cost of your life.
That's common sense
to my subordinates.
私の部下なら当たり前の事
イエス ユア・ハイネス
Yes, Your Highness!
おっ おい！　識別信号が
分からないのか？　味方だぞ！
Hey! Can't you read the I.D. signal?!
I'm on your side!
チッ
畜生ー！
Dammit!
うっ
確認しない？　なら…
They didn't confirm it? Well, then...
Ｎ２ 信号を発信して病院跡地まで後退
N2, transmit signal and
fall back to the hospital ruins.
Ｒ１ Ｒ２は待ち伏せて
追ってくる敵を撃て
R1, R2, hold positions and
fire on any pursuing enemies!
また信号か という事は…
Another signal. Which means...
その先に伏兵がいる
グロースターを増援して包囲しろ
They've set an ambush!
Send more Gloucesters and surround them!
追ってこない？　まずい！
They're not following? Uh-oh!
Ｒ１ Ｒ２ 待ち伏せ中止
直ちに退却！
R1, R2! Cancel the ambush
and fall back at once!
グロースター 指定地域に到着
敵影 見当たりません
Gloucesters have arrived at indicated area.
No sign of enemy.
こちらの手を読んだか？　本当にゼロを
相手にしているのかもしれんな
He anticipated my move? We may really
be dealing with Zero himself here.
Ｐ２ Ｎ３ 敵後方へ回り込め
どうした？　応答しろ Ｐ２ Ｎ３！
P2! N3!
Circle around behind the enemy!
What's wrong?! Come in!
P2! N3! Dammit! B1! B5! You go!
くそっ Ｂ１ Ｂ５ お前達が行け
冗談じゃねえ！　コーネリアの親衛隊
相手に勝てる訳がねえだろっ
Like hell! There's no way we
can beat Cornelia's royal guard!
おーい 降参だ
Hey! We surrender!
抵抗はしない
We won't resist!
助けてくれ
Spare us!
殺せ
Kill them.
うわっ
うおっ
Ｐ６ Ｐ８ どうした？
P6! P8! What's happening?!
くっ…
Ｂ７ Ｎ４のカバーに回れ！
B7! Come around and cover N4!
こちらＢ７ 別の獲物を見つけた
先にこっちをやる
This is B7! I've got another target here!
I'll get him first!
違う そいつはおとりだ Ｂ７命令に従え
No! That's a decoy!
B7, follow my orders!
何言ってんだい ここでやんなきゃ…
What are you saying?
I've gotta get him here!
下がれ！　上から来る！　Ｂ７命令を
Fall back! They'll hit you from above!
B7, follow my orders!
あっ はぁー
Idiot... B8, status report.
バカが
Ｂ８ そちらから状況を報告しろ
状況も何も… うわぁ！
Screw your status reports!
Ｂ８！
B8! Anyone who's left, report in,
starting with the P numbers!
チッ！　残っている者
Ｐナンバーから順に報告
おっ
Mission complete.
All forces, take formation number 4.
作戦終了
全軍第４フォーメーションに移行
制圧された… こんな簡単に
Beaten this easily?!
I've barely even started playing the game!
ゲームにすらなっていないぞ
シンジュクのようには いかなかったな
ゼロ
It didn't work out like
it did in Shinjuku, Zero.
それとも真似した奴か？
まあいい すぐに分かる
Or are you pretending to be him?
Well, we'll see who you are shortly.
これが組織… 違い過ぎる
So, this is what a real
organization is capable of?
全ナイトメアのパイロットに告げる
ハッチを開いて素顔を見せよ
To all Knightmare pilots.
Open your hatches and show me your faces!
はっ！
Cornelia!
コーネリア！
ふっ
繰り返す パイロットは全員ハッチを
開いて素顔を見せよ
I repeat, all pilots, open your
hatches and show me your faces!
どうなる 面通しをされたら？
What do I do?
If she sees my face herself, then...
ゼロの仮面はなくても俺の素性がバレる
Even without my Zero mask, my identity
will be revealed! That can't happen!
ダメだ それは
ギアスを使って…
Use my Geass? No, impossible.
バカな 相手を直接見なければ
通用しない
It won't work without
me looking directly at them.
敵がナイトメアでは…
The enemy are in Knightmares!
とすると 歩兵か他のパイロットに…
That leaves the infantry
and the other pilots.
無理だ 相手の数が多すぎるし
どうやって こちらを向かせる？
Forget it. There's too many of them.
How can I make them look at me?!
いや 可能か？
ゼロだと名乗ってしまえば…
No, is it possible?
What if I admit to being Zero?
しかし ナイトメアが…
But then the Knightmares will!
なら 先制攻撃をかけて強行突破
Maybe I can start shooting
and break out of here!
あり得ない コーネリアの親衛隊相手に
自殺行為だ
Impossible.
Against Cornelia's royal guard, it's suicide!
ハッチを開けよ 貴公の番だ
Open your hatch!
It's your turn!
あっ
どうした？　早くハッチを開けよ
What's wrong?
Hurry up and open your hatch!
それが…
先ほどの戦闘でハッチが不具合を
Well, my hatch was
damaged earlier in battle.
分かった では こちらで開けよう
I see.
Then we'll open it for you.
あっ
背中を向けろ
Turn around.
早くせんか！
Well? Come on!
分かりました 今すぐに
Understood. At once, sir...
ゼロだ ゼロを発見！
It's Zero!
Zero's been sighted!
なっ！
あっ
ほう やはりゼロはこういう性格か
Ah-hah! I knew Zero had that sort of personality!
バカな！
Impossible!
確保しろ 第３ 第５小隊 機乗！
Capture him!
Platoons 3 and 5, mount up!
映像捕捉 目標確認 第12…
Image detected! Target, confirmed!
I'll just have to play along!
ここは 乗るしかない
Surround the building!
Head around back!
ビルを包囲しろ　後ろに回れ
狙撃班 撃て！
Sharpshooters, open fire!
おお！
落ちたぞ！
He's fallen!
姫様 いかが致しますか？
Princess, what should we do?
うん 罠の可能性は？
Hm... Probability that it's a trap?
考えられます 本人かどうかも
分かりませんし
It could be.
We don't know if it's actually him,
はっきりしたのは総督の分析通り
プライドの高い人物 という事ですが…
but he seems as prideful
as you anticipated, Viceroy.
ならば 追うだけ無駄か
So, there's no point in chasing him.
はい　わざわざ敵の本陣に
姿を現したという事は
Right. If he purposely revealed himself directly to his
enemy, he must have an escape route already set.
逃走ルートを確保しての事かと
自己保身には長けているのかな？
Self-preservation trumps all, eh?
クロヴィスとは格が違う
それがコーネリアか
So, that's Cornelia.
She's nothing at all like Clovis!
なっ！
なぜ助けた？
Why did you save me?
だから言ったろ 死なれては困ると
Didn't I tell you?
I can't have you go dying on me.
条件が同じならば 負けはしなかった
I wouldn't have lost if the
conditions were more equal!
負け惜しみだな
それだけの条件を揃えるのも力のうちだ
Sore loser.
If only you had the power to set
the conditions you want.
だったら揃えてやるさ
Then I'll set it up.
ブリタニアに負けない俺の軍を
人を 国を！
I'll form an army which
can't lose to Britannia!
A people! A nation!
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Yukedomo kemonomichi
Walking along the animal path
Shishi yotorayoto hoe
Roaring with the lions and tigers
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Akane sasu sora no kanata ni mahoroba
Paradise lying far across a sky dyed red
幽囚の孤獨に 彷徨う青春は
Yuushuu no kodoku ni samayou seishun wa
To a youth wandering, imprisoned in loneliness
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Yowasato ikari ga sugata naki teki desu ka
Are weakness and hatred shapeless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は
Chichi yo madaware wa
Oh father, I am still...
己を知りがたし
Onore wo shirigatashi
Learning who I am
Sakidatsu anira no
As I pursue the backs I no longer see
先立つ兄らの
見えない背中を追えば
Mienai senakawo oeba
Of the elder brothers who have gone before me
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
Mayoi no hitoyo ni
In the night I spend lost
Myoujou wa izanau
The morning star beckons to me
死して終わらぬ
Shi shite owaranu
This will not end in my death
夢を焦がれども
Yume wo kogaredomo
I long for my dream
確かな君こそ我が命
Tashika na kimi kosowaga inochi
My faith in you sustains my life
Reppu no kouya de
In the windswept wilderness
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Chou yo hanayoto iki
Living with the butterflies and flowers
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
Tokoshie no haru ni sakisou maboroshi
Blooming together in a mirage of eternal Spring
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Kondaku nojunketsu
If my purity seems muddied
Kono mi wayogoretemo
And my body seems filthy
心の錦を信じていてください
Kokoro no nishiki wo shinjiteite kudasai
Please believe in the finery within my heart
母よ けして我は
Hahayo kesshite ware wa namidawo misene domo
Oh mother, I will show no tears
涙を見せねども
足下の草に露は消えもせで
Ashimoto no
They vanish like...
Kusa ni tsuyu wa kiemosede
The dew in the grass beneath my feet
誰がいる 俺の軍隊として動ける奴が
Who is there to serve in my army?
こんな時 スザクがいてくれれば
If only I could ask
Suzaku to join me...
いやっ 振り返るな
No, that ship has sailed.
He's a Britannian soldier!
あいつはブリタニアの軍人だ
戦いには出てこなくとも
俺の敵側にいる奴だ
Even if he doesn't go out to fight,
he's still my enemy.
ならば 選ぶべき答えは…
Well then,
I'll just have to choose.